Finding Aid for James J. Blanchard Papers, 1982-2002
Bentley Historical Library
- Press Office, 1982-1991
  - Audiotapes, 1982-1991
    - Cassette Tapes, 1982-1991
      - August 1982-September 1985, 102 audiocassettes (Box 196)
        - Public Health Directors' Conference Speech; Fred Douglas, [9940-SR-114]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 2], February 6, 1985; [9940-SR-114-2]; (Topics covered with Fred Douglas include property taxes in Michigan, Medicaid funding for abortions, welfare fraud, reduction in state emloyees, prison overcrowding, the new General Motors automobile plant, the pitch for the Winter Olympics training site to be in Marquette, and the Great Lakes Conference.)
            (Duration: 00:37:12)
        - Bob Bowman's 2nd Cable Show, [9940-SR-115]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1 - No Side 2], February 7, 1985; [9940-SR-115-1]; ("Governor's Report Programs" series interview with Robert "Bob" Bowman, Michigan State Treasurer.)
            (Duration: 00:30:20)
        - "Midday Magazine" with Warren Pierce: Governor & Mrs. Blanchard, Tokyo, [9940-SR-104]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 June 4; [9940-SR-104-1]; (Michigan Governor James Blanchard was being interviewed about his official state visit to China. The Governor's wife, Paula, was also interviewed. Content after 00:05:05 is commercial content.)
            (Duration: 00:09:10)
        - "Midday Magazine" with Warren Pierce: Governor Blanchard, Beijing, [9940-SR-105]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 June 6; [9940-SR-105-1]; (Michigan Governor James Blanchard was being interviewed about his official state visit to China. Content prior to 00:01:12 is a commercial for automotive products. There is static present throughout the tape, and the voices can be difficult to decipher. Content after 00:30:37 is an advertisement.)
            (Duration: 00:31:29)
        - Meeting with Governor Yang, [9940-SR-106]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1], 1984 June 10; [9940-SR-106-1]; (The recording is of a meeting between Michigan Governor James Blanchard and Chinese Governor Yang in front of an audience. The audio is very low, fuzzy, and difficult to decipher both languages, English and possibly Mandarin, present.)
            (Duration: 00:02:45)
          - [Side 2], 1984 June 10; [9940-SR-106-2]; (The volume continuously decreases as the audio tape progresses. There is static through out the recording. The audio is very low, fuzzy, and difficult to decipher both languages, English and possibly Mandarin, present.)
            (Duration: 00:07:13)
        - Rick from China, [9940-SR-107]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 June 11; [9940-SR-107-1]; (An update to the state side staff at the Governor's News Office about events and officials during the Governor's trip in China via a phone conversation. Content after 00:25:37 briefly switches to a recording of a different phone conversation, and then switches back to the original conversation.)
            (Duration: 00:26:38)
        - An Evening with the Governor, [9940-SR-108]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1], 1984 June 27; [9940-SR-108-1]; (Michigan Governor James Blanchard was interviewed by Tim Skubick of WKAR-TV about the fate of Consumers Energy nuclear power plant in Midland, Michigan as well as state of Michigan's energy industry jobs, power supply, and costs.)
            (Duration: 00:41:34)
          - [Side 2], 1984 June 27; [9940-SR-108-2]; (Michigan Governor James Blanchard and his wife Paula were interviewed by Tim Skubick of WKAR-TV. Paula discussed her opinions on political ideology of the day. Both were asked about potential Vice Presidental running mates for Democratic Presidential candidate Walter Mondale, and politics in the state of Michigan.)
            (Duration: 00:16:07)
        - MSU Interview on Presidential Politics, [9940-SR-109]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 July 11; [9940-SR-109-1]; (Michigan Governor James Blanchard discussed his views on the political process of presidential elections in the United States of America.)
            (Duration: 00:22:35)
      - September 1985-December 1985, 89 audiocassettes (Box 197)
      - January 1986-May 1986, 100 audiocassettes (Box 198)
      - May 1986-September 1986, 100 audiocassettes (Box 199)
      - September 1986-December 1986, 102 audiocassettes (Box 200)
      - January 1987-May 1987, 98 audiocassettes (Box 201)
      - May 1987-August 1987, 99 audiocassettes (Box 202)
      - September 1987-November 1987, 90 audiocassettes (Box 203)
      - December 1987-February 1988, 98 audiocassettes (Box 204)
      - March 1988-June 1988, 100 audiocassettes (Box 205)
      - June 1988-October 1988, 100 audiocassettes (Box 206)
      - October 1988-December 1988, 93 audiocassettes (Box 207)
      - January 1989-May 1989, 105 audiocassettes (Box 208)
      - May 1989-August 1989, 105 audiocassettes (Box 209)
      - September 1989-December 1989, 107 audiocassettes (Box 210)
      - January 1990-May 1990, 105 audiocassettes (Box 211)
      - May 1990-August 1990, 100 audiocassettes (Box 212)
      - August 1990-June 1991, 93 audiocassettes (Box 213)
  - Videotapes, 1983-1990
    The videotapes subseries, like the photographs subseries, came to the Press Office from disparate sources, and provides visual documentation (moving in this instance) of Governor Blanchard. These videotapes are first arranged according to format (U-Matic and VHS), then in a rough chronological order. The chronological order is bent to accommodate grouping of clear and distinct runs of tapes. These videotapes were created by agencies other than the Press Office, and the quality of the tapes ranges from poor to broadcast quality. Of special note are the "Governor's Reports with Howard Lancour," a nearly complete set of this series of interviews, and the "Ask the Governor" tapes of J.P. McCarthy interviews with Blanchard. Researchers will doubtless avail themselves to the various videotapes of State of the State addresses to see the Governor's delivery of these important policy statements.
    - U-Matic format, 1983-1989
      - Governor's Reports (with Howard Lancour), Omnicom/MCTVA, 1985
        - Blanchard on State of the State, January 24, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 27:25) (Box 214)
        - Bowman on State Budget and Financial Condition, February 7, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:48) (Box 214)
        - Mansour on Medicaid Abortion Veto, February 21, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:28) (Box 214)
        - Blanchard on Medicaid Abortion Veto, March 7, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 30:09) (Box 214)
        - Austin on Seat Belt Legislation, March 21, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:09) (Box 214)
        - Kindinger on Agricultural Problems and Farm Loans, April 18, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:00) (Box 214)
        - Babcock on Mental Health and Northville Incident, May 30, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 30:00) (Box 214)
        - Pitz on Road Repairs and Mass Transit, June 13, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:41) (Box 214)
        - Babcock on Mental Health, October 15, 1985; 1 videotape (U-matic; 30:00) (Box 214)
      - Governor's Reports (with Howard Lancour), Omnicom/MCTVA, 1986
        - Blanchard on Attracting Business to Michigan, February 5, 1986; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:32) (Box 215)
        - Bowman on Gramm-Rudman, February 19, 1986; 1 videotape (U-matic; 30:00) (Box 215)
        - Blanchard on Income Tax Rollback, March 5, 1986; 1 videotape (U-matic; 30:00) (Box 215)
        - Blanchard on Executive Corps, March 19, 1986; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:45) (Box 215)
        - Blanchard on Property Tax, April 1, 1986; 1 videotape (U-matic; 30:48) (Box 215)
        - Blanchard on Property Tax, April 16, 1986; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:52) (Box 215)
        - Allen on Michigan's Business Ombudsman, April 30, 1986; 1 videotape (U-matic; 29:41) (Box 215)
        - Bales and Muer on Sesquicentennial (29:44), May 7, 1986 (Box 215)
      - Blanchard's State of the State (30:00, dubbed April 9, 1987), January 1983 (Box 215)
      - Blanchard Series, WSBT-TV (South Bend), May 4-6, 1983 (Box 215)
      - Blanchard "On the Record," WZZM-TV (Grand Rapids), August 14, 1983 (Box 215)
      - "Ask the Governor," MSU-TV (East Lansing) (20:00), February 28, 1984 (Box 216)
      - Blanchard Montage, WZZM-TV (Grand Rapids), June 18, 1984 (Box 216)
      - "An Evening with the Governor; At the Residence," MSU-TV, June 27, 1984 (Box 216)
      - Michigan Infrastructure Coalition, Future Media, May 2, 1985 (Box 216)
      - Michigan Youth Corps, Department of Labor (7:40), October 23, 1985 (Box 216)
      - Blanchard Speech to Gannett News Service, Total Video (24:00), December 11, 1985 (Box 216)
      - Sesquicentennial Slides, Ross Roy (18:03), January 23, 1986 (Box 216)
      - Governor's Commission on Jobs/Steelcase Expansion, May 29 and June 13, 1986 (Box 216)
      - Blanchard's Speech to Michigan Democratic Convention (Flint), August 23, 1986 (Box 216)
      - Flood Damage (9:20), October 6, 1986 (Box 216)
      - Blanchard Inauguration, Future Media (Lansing) (45:00 on 3 tapes), January 1, 1987 (Box 216)
      - Blanchard's State of the State (59:48), January 1987 (Box 217)
      - Blanchard on MET on "Today Show," Such Video, January 28, 1987 (Box 217)
      - Department of Education on Student Financial Aid, Such Video, Spring?, 1987 (Box 217)
      - "Michigan: State of the Future," Ross Roy (12:15), June 22, 1987 (Box 217)
      - Blanchard Welcomes NGA to Michigan on "Today Show," WPBN-TV (Traverse City) (5:00), July 24, 1987 (Box 217)
      - Blanchard Welcomes Governors to Michigan, Such Video, July 25, 1987 (Box 217)
      - State of the State 1985, 1988 (55:00 dubbed May 4, 1988) (Box 217)
      - State of the State, Future Media (17:00), February 1988 (Box 217)
      - "Ask the Governor," hosted by J.P. McCarthy, December 7, 1988 (Box 217)
      - Single Business Tax Repeal, Future Media (6:18), December 21, 1988 (Box 217)
      - Blanchard Tours Jobwarp with Kids, April 5, 1989 (Box 217)
      - "Michigan: More Than Just Another Pretty State," Film Michigan/OFTRA, undated (Box 217)
      - Portrait of America: Michigan, TBS (Atlanta), undated (Box 217)
    - VHS format, 1983-1990
      - A Conversation with Governor Blanchard, WNMU-TV, January 8, 1983; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 27:55) (Box 218)
      - UP Expo, 1983; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 12:00) (Box 218)
      - State of the State, January 18, 1984 (Box 218)
      - "A Chance to Work," (Michigan Youth Corps), WTVS-TV, May 1, 1984; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 29:20) (Box 218)
      - Governor's Report on Income Tax Rollback (with Howard Lancour), 1985 (Box 218)
      - Blanchard Throws out First Pitch at Tigers Spring Game, March?, 1986 (Box 218)
      - Chrysler Tech Center Groundbreaking (Auburn Hills), October 30, 1986; 2 videotapes (VHS [TM]) (Box 218)
      - "Making it in Michigan," Independent Insurance Agents, November 1986 (Box 218)
      - NMU, Great Lakes Sports Training Center, USOC Training Center, December 1986 (Box 218)
      - Kalamazoo Math and Science Center Dedication, June 10, 1987; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 75:00) (Box 218)
      - "The Magic of Motown," NGA (Traverse City), July 25-29, 1987; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 95:00) (Box 218)
      - Labor Day Bridge Walks, Future Media, 1985-September 1987 (Box 218)
      - "Walk Michigan '87," Future Media, Fall 1987; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 7:30) (Box 218)
      - ITI/Michigan Science Foundation (University of Michigan), Satellite News Feed, October-November, 1987 (Box 218)
      - Motown Dedication, Radio/TV Reports, December 1, 1987 (Box 218)
      - State of the State, January 20, 1988 (Box 218)
      - State of the State/Response, WKAR, January 20, 1988; 2 videotapes (VHS [TM]; 60:00) (Box 218)
      - Council of Great Lakes Governors, February 3, 1988; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 54:00) (Box 218)
      - "Walk Michigan" Composite, Future Media, February 4, 1988; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 20:00) (Box 218)
      - Democratic Platform Committee Hearing, May 10, 1988; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 90:00) (Box 218)
      - Democratic Platform Committee Deliberations, CSPAN, June 15, 1988 (Box 218)
      - Blanchard, Democratic National Convention Introduction, July 14, 1988 (Box 218)
      - "Dems of Our Lives," (1988 Campaigns), Berenson/CNN, July 17, 1988 (Box 218)
      - Blanchard, Democratic National Convention, CSPAN, July 19, 1988 (Box 218)
      - MET Call-in Show, August?, 1988 (Box 218)
      - Blanchard on MET, CBS Morning Show, September 6, 1988 (Box 218)
      - "Ask the Governor," hosted by J.P. McCarthy, WKBD-TV, September 1988; 2 videotapes (VHS [TM]) (Box 218)
      - Blanchard, Marilyn McKay's Autograph Show, November?, 1988; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 29:10) (Box 219)
      - AIDS Prevention Program PSAs, 1988; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 4:00) (Box 219)
      - Michigan Department of Agriculture PSAs, 1988; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 1:30) (Box 219)
      - Michigan Farm Bureau: "Promotion and Education-Opportunities Unlimited,", 1988; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 12:11) (Box 219)
      - A Look at Your Michigan State Police PSA, 1988; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 12:00) (Box 219)
      - "Stockbridge on Target,", 1988; 2 videotapes (VHS [TM]) (Box 219)
      - Blanchard on Bush Administration, "Today Show,", January 20, 1989 (Box 219)
      - State of the State Rehearsal, Future Media, February 5, 1989 (Box 219)
      - State of the State Reception, Future Media, February 7, 1989 (Box 219)
      - "Ask the Governor," hosted by J.P. McCarthy, WKBD-TV, March 28, 1989 (Box 219)
      - "Jobwarp," Commerce Department, March 30-April 5, 1989 (Box 219)
      - Michigan Youth Corps Tree Planting (Detroit), May 5, 1989 (Box 219)
      - "Safely Managing Low-Level Radioactive Waste in Michigan," Future Media, May 16, 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 22:00) (Box 219)
      - Oakland Press Perspective, hosted by Neil Munro, June 16, 1989 (Box 219)
      - Celebrate the Great Lakes, United Cable, July 20, 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 15:00) (Box 219)
      - Blanchard at Lumbertown Parade, July 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 10:00) (Box 219)
      - Orbital Engine-Michigan Plant Announcement, Commerce Department, August 2, 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 10:00) (Box 219)
      - Blanchard Signing Quality of Life Bond Bill (Milan), Future Media, August 22, 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 19:00) (Box 219)
      - Blanchard Signing Education Bill, August 30, 1989 (Box 219)
      - Robert Mitchell, "Off the Record," hosted by Tom Skubick, WKAR-TV, September 1, 1989 (Box 219)
      - National Education Summit (Pickney), Future Media, September 22, 1989 (Box 219)
      - "Investing in Your Child's Future (MET)," WTVS, September 29, 1989 (Box 219)
      - State-Wide Exclusionary Screen and Candidate Area Selection Process (Low-Level Radioactive Waste), Future Media, September 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 9:15) (Box 219)
      - "Ask the Governor," hosted by J.P. McCarthy, WKBD-TV, October 27, 1989 (Box 219)
      - "Neighbors and Friends" (Michigan-Ontario), Ross Roy, November 1, 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 3:51) (Box 219)
      - Michigan Youth Corps/Michigan Theatre Project, November 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 8:30) (Box 219)
      - Janet Blanchard at Focus: Hope, December 8, 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 1:20) (Box 219)
      - MET: College Bound, 1989; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 21:00) (Box 219)
      - State of the State, "Up Front" WXYZ-TV, January 11, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Engler Campaign Stop (Traverse City), January 1990 (Box 220)
      - Children's Trust Fund, "Public Affairs Today,", January 1990 (Box 220)
      - Blanchard's Schools of Tomorrow, February 28-March 20, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 16:00) (Box 220)
      - "Ask the Governor," hosted by J.P. McCarthy, WKBD-TV, March 28, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Blanchard on Environment, April 6, 1990 (Box 220)
      - "You Can Make a Difference," Future Media, April 18, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 55:00) (Box 220)
      - Earth Day 1990 Future Media, April 22, 1990, 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 17:05) (Box 220)
      - Flint River Clean Up, April 28, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Blanchard at Economics Club of Grand Rapids, May 7, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Blanchard Remarks to Task Force on Inter-national Trade, May 14, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Griffiths' Retirement Announcement, May 1990 (Box 220)
      - Downriver Community Dinner, May?, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Children's Trust Fund, May?, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 43:56) (Box 220)
      - Blanchard Interview with MEAPAC, MVP Communications, June 10, 1990 (Box 220)
      - "Freddie Mac"/MSHDA, Future Media, July 2, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 63:00) (Box 220)
      - Blanchard at Macomb Chamber of Commerce, July 13, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Blanchard on Shoreline Tour (Houghton), July 1990 (Box 220)
      - "America Salutes Michigan," AMC, July 25, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 27:31) (Box 220)
      - Blanchard on Gasoline Prices, August 21, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Michigan Democratic Convention, September 5, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Blanchard Signing Polluters Pay Bill, Future Media, October 8, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 9:40) (Box 220)
      - Blanchard Speech to SWCCC Legislative Forum, October 26, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Engler "Off The Record," hosted by Tom Skubick, October?, 1990 (Box 220)
      - Blanchard For Governor Campaign Spots
        - Boot Camp, October?, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 0:30) (Box 220)
        - Taxes, October?, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 0:30) (Box 220)
        - Final, November 1, 1990; 1 videotape (VHS [TM]; 0:30) (Box 220)
      - "Michigan's Upper Peninsula: Historic, Majestic, and Unspoiled,", undated (Box 220)
- Upper Peninsula Office, 1983-1990
  The Upper Peninsula Office, 1983-1990 series consists of four linear feet of correspondence, memoranda, trip itineraries, briefing and background materials, and topical files. This series documents the efforts of Thomas Baldini, the governor's liaison to the constituents and elected officials of the entire Upper Peninsula. The materials are arranged in five subseries: correspondence, county files, education, Governor's U.P. trips, and topical. The correspondence, county, and topical subseries provide various points of access to the local concerns of U.P. constituents. These materials are a rich, diverse source on such issues as education, the environment, employment, prison construction, poor utility service, and Native American concerns as they are manifested in the Upper Peninsula in the 1980s. The education subseries is somewhat anomalous in that its geographic coverage is state-wide. This is due to the fact that Baldini was Blanchard's education advisor during part of his tenure. The Governor's U.P. trips subseries is the richest body of materials in this series. These eight folders contain a wealth of information on U.P. concerns including: briefing and background materials, itineraries, and local issues affecting county or region residents. Researchers should consult these folders first for the most coherent picture of regional concerns.
  - Correspondence, 1984-1990
    - Baldini, 1987-1990; 4 folders (Box 221)
    - Blanchard, 1984-1990; 7 folders (Box 221)
    - Constituent (A-Z), 1984-1990; 22 folders (Box 221)
  - County Files, 1984-1990
    - Alger (Box 222)
    - Baraga (Box 222)
    - Chippewa (Box 222)
    - Delta, 3 folders (Box 222)
    - Dickinson (Box 222)
    - Gogebic (Box 222)
    - Houghton (Box 222)
    - Iron (Box 222)
    - Keweenaw (Box 222)
    - Luce (Box 222)
    - Mackinac (Box 222)
    - Marquette, 4 folders (Box 222)
    - Menominee, 2 folders (Box 222)
    - Ontongan (Box 222)
    - Schoolcraft (Box 222)
  - Education Files (Thomas Baldini, Education Advisor), 1983-1990
    - Correspondence, 1983-1989; 5 folders (Box 223)
    - Memoranda, 1983-1986 (Box 223)
    - School Finance, 1988-1989 (Box 223)
    - Telecommunications, 1989-1990 (Box 223)
    - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, 1983-1990 (Box 223)
  - Governor's U.P. Trips
    - 1985-1990, 8 folders (Box 223)
  - Topical Files, 1984-1990
    - Blanchard, Janet (Box 224)
    - Blanchard, Paula (Box 224)
    - Calumet Historic Park (Box 224)
    - Capitol for a Day (Surveys) (Box 224)
    - Champion-Quinnesec (Box 224)
    - Escanaba Sign Shop (Box 224)
    - James River Site Information (Box 224)
    - Long-Term Care Study, in the U.P., 1987 (Box 224)
    - Low Level Radioactive Waste (Box 224)
    - Mackinac Bridge Task Force (Box 224)
    - Marquette (Box 224)
    - Marquette Lower Harbor Ore Dock (Box 224)
    - Mead Corporation (Box 224)
    - Menominee
      - Landfill (Box 224)
      - Wastewater Treatment (Box 224)
    - Mesquite (Box 224)
    - Michigan State Employees Association (Box 224)
    - Michigan Iron Industry Museum (Box 224)
    - Michigan Technological University
      - General (Box 224)
      - Pelletech Project (Box 224)
    - Military Bases (Box 224)
    - National Guard-Michigan (Box 224)
    - National Ski Hall of Fame (Box 224)
    - Native Americans
      - Assistance (Box 224)
      - Commission on Indian Affairs (Box 224)
      - Issues (Box 224)
    - Naturalization Certification (Box 224)
    - Northern Michigan University (Box 224)
    - Nursing Home Issues (Box 224)
    - Prisoners (Box 225)
    - Prisons, 1985-1990; 4 folders (Box 225)
    - Pulp and Paper Mills (Box 225)
    - RACO Missile Base (Box 225)
    - Railroads, 1984-1990; 3 folders (Box 225)
    - Reserve Mining (Box 225)
    - Soo Locks (Box 225)
    - Specific Ore Tax (Box 225)
    - Tri-State Home Issue (Box 225)
    - United States Olympic Committee
      - Colorado Springs Trip (Box 225)
      - Committee Meetings (Box 225)
      - Media Coverage (Box 225)
      - Portland, Oregon Trip (Box 225)
      - State Games (Box 225)
      - Training Site (Box 225)
    - Upper Peninsula
      - Airline Service (Box 225)
      - Association of County Commissioners (Box 225)
      - Harness Raceway/Fairgrounds (Box 225)
      - Highway Study (Box 225)
      - Hospitals (Box 225)
      - Medical Concerns (Box 225)
    - Ventures Group (Box 225)
    - Veterans Facility Audit (Box 225)
    - Wawatam, Chief (Box 225)
    - White Pine Mine (Box 225)
- Washington Office, 1983-1990
  The Washington Office, 1983-1990 series consists of twenty-one linear feet of correspondence, memoranda, budget materials, reports, testimony before Congress, legislation, and topical files which document fairly the office's efforts to protect Michigan's interests in budgetary, economic, employment, environmental, and human services issues. The materials are arranged in five subseries according to the person who created or used the record: E. Douglas Frost (Director), Rosemary Freeman (Assistant Director), James Callow (Analyst), Maura Cullen (Analyst), and Peter Kyriacopolous (Analyst). Within these subseries, there are some materials generated by the legislative analysts who predated them: Jane Snowden who preceded Cullen, and Charlie Moses and Jo Ellen D'Arcy who worked before Kyriacopolous. In each of these subseries only those records generated, created, or acted upon by the staffer have been retained; for the most part reference and "for your information" files have been removed.
  - E. Douglas Frost (Director), 1983-1990